Tim Johnson

Personal Statement

As a programmer with over 5 years experience using numerous technologies (list below), I am looking to take on a senior programming role. I have excellent numeracy and IT skills, and previous roles have required me to work using multiple languages. I have had the responsibility of managing a team of colleagues, and also work well individually, managing my time efficiently.

Experience

Multiply Agency Technical Lead 2019 March - Present

I was brought on the help manage a project and bring in tools and experience in large scale software development as the current developers had more experience in smaller projects. In the initial weeks I implemented automated deployment and provided training on how to use the tools for further expansion into other areas of development, I started initial work in specifications on the next phase of the project and started migrating the ticket system into a more appropriate layout.

ICAS Ltd Technical Lead 2017 March - 2019 March

I was original brought onto the company to create and implement a SSO solution for the clients to use for each site that belonged on the ICAS domain. This was implemented and is easily expandable to sites beyond the original settings. After a few months there I introduced CI/CD in the form of TeamCity and Octopus to deploy the internal sites. This reduced the downtime of the sites and the developer volunteered to do the deployment from half a day to 7 minutes on average. Currently because I'm Tech Lead on the project I'm keeping the standards of code of any code checked into the source control system. Recently I was part of the migration from the old CRM to Dynamics 365, this mainly involved moving the backing database and creating extension methods to allow for simpler and faster code entry.

I was the Senior software developer in the company. My main tasks were maintaining the legacy systems (written in ASP.NET and T-SQL) and implementing improvements and bug fixes in the new product (using ASP.NET, MVC and Entity Developer). I successfully migrated the company to using TeamCity and am the administrator of it. One task was to optimise the T-SQL that the legacy systems were using to ensure that the servers weren't under strain for incorrect implemented queries. I've been key in helping set up the system in the cloud areas of AWS and Azure, this involved creating VMs setting up the correct resource groups and corresponding security settings.

4Sight Financial Software Technical Lead September 2014 - 2015 June

I was the Technical Lead of the Edinburgh-based team in which I have built on my skills in management. I am responsible for delegating tasks to my team and ensuring deadlines are met. I held meetings with Business Analysts to create technical specifications for my team in keeping with client

requirements.

4Sight Financial Software Consultant

April 2013 - September 2014

I worked as part of a team under a Technical Lead developing new features for a client, while adhering to the specifications. I was required to travel to the client site to ensure our software complied with their requirements. Another project involved migrating the backing database system from Oracle to Sybase. This required communication between the Edinburgh and Toronto based teams to coordinate deadlines, where I was responsible for reporting my team progress.

4Sight Financial Software
On-Site Support

March 2012 - April 2013

I acted as a first point-of-contact for the client while representing 4Sight in this support role on site abroad. I spent part of the year creating and implementing Crystal Reports and training the client's teams to use the new system. I then moved on to improving performance in the database by tuning SQL statements. This role allowed me to work directly with 4Sight clients while maintaining effective communication with my team back in the UK.

4Sight Financial Software Support

December 2011 - March 2012

I was a part of a dedicated support team, which required me to work across multiple versions of the system and clients. My knowledge of C# and Java was required to help with any issues raised by the client. Being on Support, I was also required to train colleagues on the new system. In addition to this, I learned to use PowerBuilder to help resolve issues in the legacy software.

4Sight Financial Software Graduate Developer April 2010 - December 2011

I was hired to help develop and maintain the new front-end system to replace a legacy system. I learnt about the product lifecycle and furthered my understanding of MVVM patterns. I also visited the client on site to provide support, updates and developments in the software.

Axzona Graduate Developer October 2008 - April 2010

I was the Lead programmer on the company's front end system that allowed customers to log in and view their website statistics via flash-generated graphs. It provided a detailed view, including the ability set up rules around web monitoring via drag and drop components. I used a variety of languages throughout my role with Axzona, including JQuery, SqlServer and ASP.NET/C#.

Education

BSc Hons - Computer Science Heriot-Watt University 2003 - 2007

Skills

- PowerBuilder
- Java
- Sybase
- WPF
- MVVM Pattern
- Spring
- TFS Source Control
- Entity Developer
- Azure
- MySQL
- Laravel

- C#
- PL/SQL
- ASP.NET
- Crystal Reports
- Perforce Source Control
- Hibernate
- T-SQL
- MVC
- AWS
- PHP
- Dynamics 365 API

Interests

I am an active person; I like Snowboarding with frequent trips up to Aviemore or Braehead. I cycle to and from work. I enjoy running regularly, in addition to taking part in races across the UK. I go rock climbing weekly. I like to relax by playing the computer or tabletop and board games.

References

Available on request